<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The declaracyon of the procedynge of a conference, begon at Westminster the last of Marche, 1559 concerning certaine articles of religion and the breaking vp of the sayde conference by default and contempt of certayne bysshops, parties of the sayd conference.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1560</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 12 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 9 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A14978</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 25286</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S104298</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99840036</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99840036</idno>
            <idno type="VID">4507</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A14978)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 4507)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 1614:03)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The declaracyon of the procedynge of a conference, begon at Westminster the last of Marche, 1559 concerning certaine articles of religion and the breaking vp of the sayde conference by default and contempt of certayne bysshops, parties of the sayd conference.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[16] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>By Richarde Iugge and Iohn Cawood prynters to the quenes Maiestie,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Imprynted at London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>[1560?]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Publication date from STC.</note>
                  <note>Signatures: A.</note>
                  <note>Some print blurred.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the Bodleian Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Church of England. --  Thirty-nine Articles --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-09</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-09</date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-11</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-11</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:4507:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:4507:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>¶ The declara<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cyon of the procedynge of a conference, begon at Weſtminſter the laſte of Marche. 1559. concer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning certaine articles of religion and the breaking vp of the ſayde conference by default and con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tempt of certayne Byſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhops, parties of the ſayd conference.</p>
            <p>(⸫)</p>
            <p>¶ Imprynted at London by <hi>Richarde lugge and Iohn Cawood</hi> prynters to the Quenes Maieſtie.</p>
            <p>Cum priuilegio Regiae Maieſtatis<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
            </p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:4507:2"/>
            <p>
               <hi>
                  <seg rend="decorInit">T</seg>HE</hi> Quenes mooſt excellent Maieſtye, ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uynge harde of diuerſitie of opi<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>nions in cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tayne matters of religio<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> amongeſt ſundry of hir louing ſubiectes, and beyng very deſirous to haue the ſame redu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ced to ſome godlye and chryſtian concorde, thought it beſt by thad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uiſe of the lordes and others of hir priuye counſel, aſwell for the ſatiſfaction of perſons doubtful, as alſo for the knowledge of the very trueth in certayne mater of difference: to haue a conueniente choſen nomber of the beſt learned of either parte, and to conferre to<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>gyther their opinions and rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons, and therby to come to ſome
<pb facs="tcp:4507:2"/>
good and charytable agrement.</p>
            <p>And hervppon by hir maieſtyes commaundement, certaine of hir priuye counſel, declared this pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſe to tharchbiſhop of yorke (be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ynge alſo one of the ſame priuye counſell) &amp; required him that he wolde imparte the ſame to ſome of the biſhops, and to make choiſe of. viii. ix. or. x. of them, and that ther ſhuld be the like nomber na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>med of thother parte: and further alſo declared to him (as than was ſuppoſed) what the matters ſhuld be: And as for the tyme, it was thought mete to be aſſone as poſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſible might be agreed vpon. And than after certayne dayes paſt, it was ſignified by the ſayde arche<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>byſhop, that ther was appoynted by ſuche of the byſhops to whom he had imparted thys matter.
<pb facs="tcp:4507:3"/>
viii. perſons, that is to ſaye. iiii. byſhops and. iiii. doctours, who were content at the Quenes ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ieſties commaundement to ſhe we their opinions, and as he termed it, render accompte of their fayth in thoſe matters which were me<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cioned, and that ſpecially in wri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tynge, althoughe he ſayde they thought the ſame ſo determined, as ther was no cauſe to dyſpute vpon them. It was hervpon ful<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly reſolued by the quenes maieſty with thaduiſe aforeſayd, that ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to their deſire, it ſhuld be in writing on both partes, for a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uoydyng of muche altercation in wordes, and that the ſaid biſhops ſhuld bicauſe thei wer in auctho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rytie, of degree ſuperiours: fyrſte declare their myndes and opiny<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons to the matter, with their rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons
<pb facs="tcp:4507:3"/>
in writynge, and the o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther nomber being alſo. viii. men of good degree in ſcooles, &amp; ſome hauinge ben in dygnitye in the churche of Englande, if they had any thing to ſay to the contrary, ſhould the ſame day declare their opynions in lyke maner. And ſo eche of them ſhould delyuer their writynges to thother, to be con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſydered what were to be impro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ued therin, &amp; the ſame to declare agayne in writing at ſome other conuenient daye, and the lyke or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der to be kept in all the reſt of the matters: al this was fully agreed vpon with tharchbiſhop of yorke and ſo alſo ſignified to both par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties. And immediatlye herevpon, dyuerſe of the nobility and ſtates of the realme, vnderſtanding that ſuche a metynge and conference
<pb facs="tcp:4507:4"/>
ſhoulde be, and that in certayne matters wherupon the courte of parliament conſequentlye follo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wing ſome lawes might be grou<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded: they made erneſt meanes to hir maieſtie, that the partyes of thys conference, myght put and reade their aſſertions in theng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lyſhe tonge, and that in the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſence of them of the nobility and others of hir parlyament houſe, for the better ſatiſfaction &amp; inha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bling of their owne Iudgments to treate and conclude of ſuche lawes as myght depende herevp<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on. This alſo beyng thought ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rye reaſonable, was ſignifyed to both parties, and ſo fully agreed vppon, and the day apoynted for the firſt meting to be the Friday in the forenone being the laſte of March at Weſtminſter churche,
<pb facs="tcp:4507:4"/>
where bothe for good order &amp; for honour of the conference by the Quenes maieſties commaunde<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment the lordes and others of the priuy counſell were preſent, and a great part of the nobility alſo, and notwithſtandyng the former order appoynted and conſented vnto by bothe partes, yet the biſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhop of Wincheſter and his colle<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gees alleging they had miſtaken, that their aſſertions and reaſons ſhuld be wryten, and ſo only reci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted out of the booke, ſayde their booke was not ready then write<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>, but thei were ready to argue and diſpute, and therfore they would for that tyme repeate in ſpeache that which they had to ſay to the firſt propoſicion. This varyacion from the former order and ſpecy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ally from that which them ſelfes
<pb facs="tcp:4507:5"/>
had by the ſayde archebyſhop in writing before required, addinge thereto the reaſon of the apoſtle, that to contende wyth wordes is profitable to nothing, but to ſub<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>uerſio<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> of the hearer: ſemed to the Quenes maieſties counſell ſome what ſtraunge, &amp; yet was it per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted without any great repre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>henſion, bycauſe they excuſed the<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> ſelfes with miſtakinge the order, and agreed that they woulde not fayle but put it in writynge, and accordyng to the former order, de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lyuer it to the other parte, and ſo the ſaid biſhop of Wincheſter and his collegees appointed Doctour Cole Deane of Poules, to be the vtterer of their minds, who part<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly by ſpeche onely, and partly by readyng of authorytyes wryten, and at certayne tymes beyng en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>formed
<pb facs="tcp:4507:5"/>
of hys collegees what to ſay: made a declaracyon of their meaninges and their reaſons to their firſt ꝓpoſicion, which being ended, they were aſked by the pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uy counſel if any of theim had a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny more to be ſaied: and they ſaid no. So as the<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> thother parte was lycenced to ſhewe their myndes, which they did accordynge to the firſte order, exhybitynge all that which thei ment to be propound, in a booke wryten, which after a prayer &amp; inuocacion made moſte humbly to almyghty god for the enduyng of theim with his holye ſprite, and a proteſtacion alſo to ſtande to the Doctrine of the ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tholyke Church builded vpon the ſcripturs, and the doctrine of the prophetes and thapoſtles: was diſtynctlye read by one Roberte
<pb facs="tcp:4507:6"/>
Horne bachelour in Diuinitye, late Deane of Dureſme. And the ſame being ended with ſome like<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lyhod, as it ſeamed that the ſame was muche allowable to the au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dience: certaine of y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> Biſhops be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gan to ſaye contrary to their for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mer anſwere, that they had now much more to ſay to this matter, wherein although they myghte haue ben well reprehended for ſuche maner of cauillacyon: yet for auoydinge of any more miſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>kinge of orders in this colloquy, or conference, and for that they ſhoulde vtter all that which they had to ſaye: It was both ordered and thus openly agreed vpon of both partes in the full audience, that vppon the Mondaye follo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wing, the Byſhops ſhulde bryng their mindes and reaſons in wri<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ting
<pb facs="tcp:4507:6"/>
to the ſeconde aſſertion, and the laſt alſo if thei could, and firſt rede the ſame, and that done, tho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther parte ſhulde bryng lykewiſe theirs to the ſame. And beynge read, eche of theim ſhould deliuer to other the ſame wrytings. And in the meane tyme the byſhoppes ſhulde put in writyng, not onely al that which Doctour Cole had that day vttered: but all ſuche o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther matters as they anye other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe could thinke of for the ſame, and as ſone as they myght poſſy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble, to ſende the ſame booke tou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ching that firſt aſſertion to the o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther parte, and they ſhuld receiue of theym that wrytinge whiche Mayſter Horne had there read that day, &amp; vpon Mo<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>day it ſhuld be agreed what day thei ſhuld ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hibyte their aunſwers touching
<pb facs="tcp:4507:7"/>
the firſt propoſition. Thus both partes aſſented thereto, and the aſſemblye quietly diſmiſſed. And therfore vpon Mondaye, the lyke aſſemblye began agayne at the place and hower appoynted, and ther vpon what ſiniſter or dyſor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dered meaninge is not yet fullye knowen (though in ſome part it be vnderſta<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ded) the biſhop of Win<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>cheſter and his Collegees, and eſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pecially Lyncolne, refuſed to ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hibite or reade, accordynge to the former notorious order on friday that which they had prepared for the ſecond aſſertion. And therup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on by the Lord keper of the great leale, they being firſt gently and fauourable required to kepe thor der appointed, &amp; that takinge no place, beinge ſecondly as it beho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ued, preſſed wyth more earneſt requeſte: they neyther regardyng
<pb facs="tcp:4507:7"/>
the aucthoritye of that place, nor their owne reputacyon, nor the credite of the cauſe, vtterly re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuſed that to do. And finallye be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>inge againe perticulerly euery of theim a part diſtinctlye by name required, to vnderſtand their opi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nions therin: they all ſauing one (which was the Abbot of Weſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>minſter, hauinge ſome more con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſideration of order and his dutye of obedience then thother) vtter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly &amp; plainly denied to haue their boke read, ſome of theim as more erneſtly then other, ſome ſo alſo, ſome other more vndiſcretly, and vnreuere<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>tlye then others. When vpon geuing ſuch example of dyſ<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>order, ſtubbernes &amp; ſelfe wyll, as hath not ben ſene and ſuffered in ſuch an honorable aſſembly, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ynge of the two eſtates of this Realme the nobility and the com<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>mons,
<pb facs="tcp:4507:8"/>
beſyde the preſence of t<gap reason="illegible" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap> Quenes maieſties moſt honor<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>
               <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ble priuy cou<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ſel, y<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>e ſame aſſemblye was diſmiſſed, &amp; the godly &amp; moſt chriſtia<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> purpoſe of y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> Quenes ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ieſtye made fruſtrate. And after<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ward for y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>tempt ſo notoriouſly made, y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> Byſhops of Wyncheſter &amp; Lincoln, hauing moſt obſtinatly both diſobeied common auctority and varied manifeſtly from their owne order, &amp; ſpecially Lincoln, who ſhewed more folly then tho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther: were condingely committed to the Tower of London, and the reſt (ſauyng y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> abbot of Weſtmin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter) ſtand bounde to make daylye their perſonall apparaunce be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the counſell, and not to de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>parte the Cytye of London and Weſtminſter, vntill further order be taken with theim for their diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>obedience and contempte.</p>
            <div type="part">
               <pb facs="tcp:4507:8"/>
               <head>¶ The three propoſityons wher vpon conference was determined to haue bene at weſtminſter.</head>
               <p n="1">1 It is againſt the worde of god, and the cuſtum of the auncient church, to vſe a tong vnknow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>en to the people, in co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>mon prai<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er, and the admyniſtration of the ſacramentes.</p>
               <p n="2">2 Euery church hath authoritie to appoint take away &amp; change ceremonyes and eccleſiaſtycall rites, ſo y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> ſame be to edificacio<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>.</p>
               <p n="3">3 It cannot be proued by y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> word of god, that ther is in the Maſſe offred vp a Sacrifyce for the quicke and the dead.</p>
            </div>
         </div>
         <div type="list_of_participants">
            <pb facs="tcp:4507:9"/>
            <head>The names of ſuch as had conference in the propo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſitions aforeſaid.</head>
            <list>
               <item>The B. of winch.</item>
               <item>The B. of Lych.</item>
               <item>The B. of Cheſt.</item>
               <item>The B. of Carliſ.</item>
               <item>The B. of Linco.</item>
               <item>Doctour Cole.</item>
               <item>D. Harpeſfolde.</item>
               <item>Doct. Langdall.</item>
               <item>Doctor Chedſey.</item>
               <item>D. Sco. B. of Chyc.</item>
               <item>Doctour Coxe</item>
               <item>Maiſter Whithed</item>
               <item>Mayſter Grindall</item>
               <item>Mayſter Horne.</item>
               <item>Maiſter D. Sandes.</item>
               <item>Maiſter Geſt.</item>
               <item>Mayſter Aylmer.</item>
               <item>Mayſter Iuell.</item>
            </list>
            <closer>God ſaue the Quene.</closer>
            <pb facs="tcp:4507:9"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
